John Webster

7550 Folsom Auburn Rd Apt. 202 Folsom CA 95630 Cell phone: (916) 792 8734 Email: JohnLobster@comcast.net

Summary

Full stack developer with 30 years experience in computer industry looking for challenging and rewarding work in web design, local to Folsom/Sacramento area

Links

LinkedIn: www.LinkedIn.com/in/JohnWWebster

Github: https://github.com/johnlobster

Portfolio: https://johnlobster.github.io/portfolio/

March-August 2019 : UC Davis bootcamp - Full stack web development

Key full stack technologies

MERN - MongoDb, Express, React, Node

HTML, CSS, Javascript, mySQL, git

Other full stack libraries/technologies

Vscode, Trello, npm, mongoose, sequelize, handlebars, lodash, mocha, chai, chai-http, postman, bcrypt, react-router, cheerio, moment, sass, jsonwebtoken, winston, bootstrap, materialize, create-react-app, Jquery, github, travisCl, heroku, eslint, axios, firebase, bash

Management experience

- Managed small teams (to 5 people). Mentoring of junior engineers.
- Delivered technical training and taught Intel core values classes
- cross site/geography working

Other skills

- · Good communication skills
- Results focused ability to rapidly learn or develop new methodologies, tools and flows
- · Great debugging skills

Work history

Intel Corporation (Folsom, CA) September 1996 – July 2015. Senior component design engineer

2007 - 2015 Integrated graphics (VPG) - Technology team, part of physical design team

- VPG supplies integrated graphics for Intel CPUs using ASIC methodologies.
- Power grid design and analysis for integrated graphics re-used on many other ASIC products within Intel
- First tapeouts on 22nm (Haswell), 14nm (Broadwell),10nm (CanonLake).

- Design of metal patterns as part of Intel process definition team, design metal stack, reliability tradeoffs, density tradeoffs, library design tradeoffs (Intel award)
- Design of power gate placement and connection scheme analysis of area impact and Electromigration
- Local expert on reliability, Antenna checks, ESD cell placement and many layout only features.

2005-2006 Integrated graphics (VPG): SandyBridge (28nm) - first Intel CPU with integrated graphics

- · layout design lead, tapeout of Integrated Graphics, owned display block tapeout
- Convergence of physical design and reliability flows between CPU team (custom approaches) and graphics (ASIC approach) std cell library, runset, database, fill methodologies, layout database, reliability (EM)

1997-2005 (PCI chipsets physical design)

- Broadwater chip set (integrated graphics)
- Backend lead for Plumas chipset, first server chipset within PCI chipset division.
- RTL to gates lead for several test chips and validation chips

1996-1997 Pre-silicon validation of 440BX chip set – single die North Bridge for Intel CPU

• Definition of tests, integration of bus models, writing tests, execution and regressions, owned DRAM testing (no errors in silicon)

ARM Ltd (Cambridge, England) 1993 - 1996

- Definition and initial support of AMBA bus standard
- Design of ARM8 integer pipeline (VHDL)
- Support and testing of VHDL wrapper for ARM software model.

Inmos Ltd (Bristol, England) 1987 - 1991

- Design of Floating Point Unit for next generation microprocessor (transputer) performance analysis, algorithm design, definition, hdl design and simulation, custom design and layout of add/subtract unit. Integration into integer pipeline. Formal verification. Synopsys DC used for control logic synthesis.
- Board testing and design completion

Education:

B.Eng Computer Systems Engineering (First class honors) 1984-1987 University of Bristol Internship at Ferranti Computer Systems Ltd., Bracknell 1983-1986

Chip design tools and skills

Physical Design.

Antenna (NAC), LVS, DRC, netlisting. Synthesis, Routing, Static timing analysis and timing closure in ASIC environment. Design rules and the underlying process technology. Layer densities, Physical Design for Debug (fiducials, fib cells, spare cells). Fill mechanisms, tech files setup. Tapeouts at 22,14 and 10nm process nodes. Low power design. Formal Verification. Clock tree synthesis.

Power grid design and Reliability

Power grid design and analysis, area vs IR drop, Power gating, EM, on die regulation, bump analysis Tools and programming

Synopsys ICC, ICV (and Hercules), Synthesis, DC, PrimeTime, Apache Redhawk, verilog, VHDL Perl, TCL, C, lisp (emacs macros ..., mainsail)

Unix, MS word, Excel, Powerpoint. JMP, batch computeing

Design

Experience in ASIC design flow from RTL to GDS/OASIS Micro-architecture and RTL design of microprocessors

RTL verification

Debug and problem solving skills throughout ASIC design flow

Scripting for design flows and for problem solving.